[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[ENGINE REVVING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TRUCK HORN BLARES]
[LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- Stop!
- [GUNSHOT]
[FIREWORKS EXPLODING]
- [ENGINES REVVING]
- [BUS HORN HONKS]
[GLASS SHATTERING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- [GUNSHOT]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- [TRUCK HORN HONKS]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
Victor tried to kill me!
My life is in danger.
If you want to survive,
you need to work with us.
That Delgado's so arrogant.
Dig into Director Delgado's
records.
I'm sure we can find something
we can use against him.
I'm asking for something
so simple.
Get over here
before I make you regret it!
Come with us.
You explain it to Umali.
Just a reminder, okay?
We came here to have fun.
Let's forget everything
that happened.
All the food I'm feeding you
is delicious!
And I'll make sure
you're drowning in booze.
We caught Mr. Chan, but
we're the ones taking the fall.
Ma'am Pia's furious at you,
and Delgado's mad at us.
I'll head to the bar
so we can order.
- Thank you.
- You shouldn't have.
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
[SNIFFLES]
Ma'am.
[SNIFFLES, EXHALES SOFTLY]
Oh...
Are you still mad
about Salvador?
Sir Umali said
they'd handle it
I just feel bad for my dad.
I feel so sorry for him.
He's retired, yet they keep
bothering him.
He doesn't talk about it,
but I know him well.
I can feel how deeply
this is affecting him.
And freezing development in
Ginintuang Lupa made it worse.
I need to do something
to help him out.
Ma'am...
How are you going to do that,
Ma'am?
Salvador keeps throwing
new allegations around.
Then I will solve this problem
myself.
I'm going to make
my dad proud.
Handle Mr. Chan's transfer
to the safe house right now.
- Copy, sir.
- Okay.
Sir.
Sir, are you really trusting
him with the transfer?
Why, Pia?
Is there an issue?
There's no issue,
just like with Jacinto.
Sir, why not just give
the job to Tuazon?
He's good at his job.
He listens to orders
and never acts out like others.
I can't assign Team Alpha
to the transfer
because they disobeyed me.
Sir, Tuazon wasn't even
one of the troublemakers.
To be fair.
My decision is final.
[BROODING MUSIC PLAYING]
[LIVELY MUSIC PLAYING]
What are we going to do?
We're dead if they find out.
[BARTENDER]
Yeah, I'll bring it over.
- One for table number two.
- Got it.
- Uh... boss?
- Yeah.
- Excuse me.
- Boss...
- I'd like to order a--
- We'd like to order.
- Yeah, and add one of those.
- Uh, boss?
- I'd like to order a--
- Hold on, I'm busy!
- What can I get you?
- Is our order ready yet?
- Yeah, I'll bring it over.
- Alright, thanks.
Gabo really is amazing,
isn't he?
Even though people look down
on our neighborhood,
and Miss Betchay constantly
belittles him,
they don't know how good
his heart actually is.
Imagine, all that gold,
and he just returned it.
He's likely the last person
who behaves that way.
I'm not even surprised
about that.
He's always been like that
since we were young.
They're targeting him here,
but he has a good heart.
You guys think
way too highly of Gabo.
Maybe he's just saying that.
He probably has a cut
of the gold he got.
- That's true.
- [TOLITS] Right?
Anyone who sees
that much gold
will get tempted to steal
a bit to have a better life.
Don't just believe Gabo blindly.
You're forgetting he's
from Ginintuang Lupa.
- We all think alike.
- Hey, hey!
Stop saying that about Gabo.
Just because
we're from the same place
doesn't mean
you know him like that.
You haven't been with
him since we were children.
And you three...
If you don't trust him,
then leave!
Go back to Django!
We're just thinking rationally.
We all have
different ways of thinking.
We're thinking rationally.
It's hard to trust someone.
Just shut up.
[SEBASTIAN] Why did you do it?
What were you thinking, Sam?
You didn't inform us
about your plan.
To me!
I could've helped you!
Look at what happened.
Your service was inconvenienced
because of what you guys did.
I know.
It was just me.
I didn't follow the protocol.
I just really want
to catch Mr. Chan.
Because I knew he'd be
the key to finding more
about Zafra's illegal plans.
His family has such
a big influence.
[KAREN] What kind of mess
did we get ourselves into?
It's so hard to get out of.
I'm sorry, team.
I'm really sorry.
[KAREN] Sam,
stop blaming yourself.
We know what we did,
and we did it willingly.
We want to support you here.
If we get suspended or
if we get dismissed from duty,
we will not regret it.
The food is taking too long.
I'll go to the bathroom.
[DABOY] I'll go with you!
- [TOLITS] Let's go.
- I'll leave you, guys.
- Let's go.
- C'mon.
Do you guys see that?
Those three
have terrible attitudes.
Boss, I'd like to place
an order, please.
- [BOTTLE RATTLES]
- Can't you see I'm busy?
I don't regret what we did.
We might get hit with a lawsuit,
and we could go to jail.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
[CELLPHONE RINGING]
- It's Sir Delgado.
- [CELLPHONE RINGS]
Ah...
- Answer it!
- What will I say?
- Anything!
Maybe he just wants
to ask something.
Gabo?
Have you ordered?
I'm starving.
He might hear
that we're at a bar.
- Let's go!
- [GABO] He's ignoring me!
[TOLITS] Alright.
I'll use the bathroom first.
- Let's go.
- I'll come with you.
- [CELLPHONE RINGING]
- No, we'll handle it.
[CELLPHONE RINGING]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Do you have any idea
what happened?
[PAQUITO] A man intervened.
They robbed Salvador.
Robbed? Did he get beaten up?
Clearly, that idiot got bolder!
He went to the police
station to file a complaint.
This means all your men
are wanted in our precinct.
[DJANGO] Well.
Aren't you police officers?
You can handle it.
You're so arrogant.
You're way too full of yourself.
You're nothing like your father!
Go ahead. Shoot me.
Let's see
how brave you are.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
[PAQUITO] Don't embarrass
yourself, Django.
Drop your guns.
Umali.
I'm sorry.
This won't happen again.
We didn't need
to reach this point.
Paquito.
We've been doing business
together for a long time.
You know me.
You didn't
do what I asked you...
So I won't pay you.
Let's go.
[GRIM MUSIC PLAYING]
Whoever did this,
better pray
that we don't cross paths
because I'll bury him alive.
Hey, boss?
Maybe I can start ordering?
My friends are starving.
Can't you see I'm busy?
We'll just have six beers
and o--
I told you I'm still busy.
I wonder why Sir Delgado
is calling.
[ROBERT] It's probably
about Ma'am Sam.
We're the ones doing
the right thing,
yet we still end up looking
like the bad guys.
Don't worry.
I will take care of all of you.
Especially you, Sam.
Are you sure
you got us, Sir Seb?
Absolutely. Sure.
- I need to use the restroom.
- Me too.
- Thank you, sir.
- I'll go with you.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Hey, boss?
Can we get
a follow-up on our order?
- Hey, boss.
- What is it?
Stop ignoring me
and take my order!
Do you want me
to hit you in the head?
You're taking other
people's orders but mine!
I'm sorry!
Will you finally
take my order?
Yes, sir!
What's your order?
Six beers, one cocktail,
one crispy pork knuckle,
barbeque, and sisig.
- Got it?
- Yes.
Are you okay, Sam?
Sam, if you need someone...
[SEBASTIAN] I'm right here.
I'll be here to listen to you.
You know what,
we could be...
I believe in you, Sam.
I'm right here for you, Sam.
[BROODING MUSIC PLAYING]
I'll cover it.
And you take care of the...
[VOICE TRAILS OFF]
Hurry, I need to pee.
[MAN GAGGING]
You keep throwing up, man!
Dude, you smell like
a sapodilla. Pack it up!
- You're too drunk, man.
- [ZIPPER ZIPS OPEN]
- It's such a waste, isn't it?
- [DOOR CLOSES]
Could a 100,000 pesos hold
a candle to a few gold bars?
Do the math for me.
[LAUGHS] If it were me,
it's all mine.
I'd keep those bars
all to myself!
But we know Gabo.
He's a thug for real!
But he has his own principles.
- He'll only do the right thing.
- [PEE SPLASHING]
What did you say?
Principles! You know,
something like, justice!
What's the use of principles
if your stomach is growling?
There was gold just within
his grasp!
If it were me, you'll never hear
from me again.
- For real? Not even us?
- [ZIPPER ZIPS CLOSE]
- Huh?
- Maybe I'll give you some.
- Just a little!
- Bastard.
- [BONG CLICKS TONGUE]
- [DOOR OPENS]
- It's Gabo.
- He's here.
Gabo, what took you so long?
Where are the food and drinks?
I'm starving and we're parched!
[QUIRKY MUSIC PLAYING]
Sam, you don't have to...
bottle your feelings up
all on your own.
You can confide in me.
I'll listen. Really.
With everything that's happened,
I got suspended.
- The team got involved.
- Hmm.
Karen got hurt too.
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
I have no idea
how to deal with this.
I don't know how I'm going
to tell my daddy about this.
[SCOFFS]
The daughter of an NLEA Chief...
is a failure.
My daddy was probably right.
I'm no good.
Sam, Sam, Sam.
That mission...
doesn't define who you are.
One more thing, you just did
what you thought was right
based on the situation at hand.
Problem is, you just violated
our protocols.
But that doesn't mean
that what you did was wrong.
That's where the problem lies.
How can I be a public servant
if I can't even abide
by the law myself?
No. Look, Sam.
Sam.
You're a leader.
Okay?
You're not a follower.
And sometimes,
you have to cross that line
to be the leader that you are.
[PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING]
- Hmm?
- [PATTING]
[PATS]
Hmm. Thanks.
Mm-hmm.
[BOTTLES CLINK]
[PENSIVE MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [BINOY] It can!
- [TOLITS] Yeah, it can--
- Shh!
- [QUIRKY MUSIC PLAYING]
[CLEARS THROAT] There's puke
all over the place!
[DOOR CREAKS CLOSE]
[ZIPPER ZIPS OPEN]
[PEE SPLASHING]
[QUIRKY MUSIC CONTINUES]
What are you looking at, huh?
Nothing.
What do you mean, nothing?
You were taking a peek.
What?
Am I your type?
No.
[BINOY] What's wrong, Daboy?
[TOLITS] Is there a problem?
Wait a minute.
I know you guys.
You're those three bastards
who ran into us in Chinatown.
Hey, who're you calling
bastards? Us?
And we didn't ran into you.
- You were blocking the way.
- Hey, Tolits, that's enough!
We're no match for them.
They're huge!
So what if they're huge?
You scared?
You think we're small?
You think he's small?
Don't point at me.
That's right? Wh-- why,
you wanna fight, huh?
Think you can get us?
You want to get a taste
of my fists?
- You, wanna go at it?
- [BLOW LANDS]
[BINOY] What happened? Huh?
[STIRRING MUSIC PLAYING]
Oh, so you're pretending
that it doesn't hurt, huh?
- He's trying to look tough.
- For sure.
You're enduring it, huh?
- Take this! [GRUNTING]
- [BLOWS LANDING]
[BINOY] Get him, Tolits!
Get his ass!
It's useless. [PANTING]
[STIRRING MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [GRUNTING]
- Do it faster! Harder!
- [BLOWS LANDING]
- [WHIMPERS]
Ow, it hurts! I'm the one
who's getting hurt.
It hurts. [INHALES SHARPLY] Ow!
[CHANTING] I don't want
to fight, I don't want to fight.
- Is that it?
- What do you mean, is that it?
- [BLOW LANDS]
- [GRUNTS IN PAIN] Ow!
- [BLOWS LANDING]
-[BINOY, TOLITS, DABOY GROANING]
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
That hurts!
You know, Sam, [CLEARS THROAT]
I was thinking...
why don't we go on a vacation?
What do you think?
We could go to Boracay.
- Or even Europe or America.
- [LAUGHS]
Maybe Australia.
Anywhere we could unwind.
Away from our problems,
from all of this.
- What do you say?
- No need. It's fine.
You sure?
I am.
Uh... okay. But don't worry,
I'll take care of your case.
Okay? I'll fix it.
Don't worry.
I got your back.
Aren't you reliable?
- Of course!
- [BOTTLES CLINK]
Count on it.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
What did Delgado say?
Was it about me?
Sam, they're already building
up a case against you.
They also want to file
a petition
against you to kick you out
of the agency.
[SEBASTIAN CLICKS TONGUE]
It's just a petition.
It's not yet the final decision.
Know what, we can still
turn things around.
We can still correct it.
Sam, when the team did
a clean up
at the area of operation,
they never found a case
containing gold bars in it.
- Where is it then?
- [RALLOS] Ma'am,
even if
it's an illegal operation,
maybe we could try to use it
as an evidence against Mr. Chan
if we find that gold.
We need to find the gold.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Oh, by the way,
where'd those three go?
To the bathroom. They still
haven't come back though.
- [GRUNTS, PANTING]
- [DABOY] Have mercy, boss!
We'll sue you!
We'll sue you with child abuse
and uh...
- libel!
- You're going to sue us
when you started it?!
Look. We're NCIA agents!
What if we beat you up
for real?!
Please don't, sir!
Let's frisk them they might
have firearms on them!
I have nothing, sir! Ow!
I don't even have money
on me, sir!
We're broke as hell, sir!
I told you, it's empty!
- Nothing.
- I got nothing, sir!
Ack! Ow!
- [ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
- [MUFFLED SCREAMS]
[DOOR OPENS]
- [SCREAMS]
- Hey, that's enough!
- What on earth happened?
- It's these bastards!
They're cocky
and messed with us!
That's enough. Let's avoid
getting into trouble. Let's go!
That's enough. Let's just go.
You should be thankful
we still have somewhere to be.
[TOLITS] Thank you!
It's your fault!
You kept staring at him!
Was he your type, huh?!
[CASTOR] Hey, guys,
why did you do that?
Come on, guys!
We're already going through
enough problems as it is.
If those men filed a complaint
against us,
we might be suspended for real.
Sorry, Tony. It's my bad.
[SIGHS]
Fix yourselves up.
Hurry up. Ma'am Sam's
waiting for us.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Sir.
Have you talked to Paquito?
Who was the man
they encountered?
Sir, they don't know.
They weren't the ones
who fought him.
They just ordered their
incompetent men to do it.
They fought one guy,
but all of them got beaten.
They're useless!
What we pay them
is just a waste.
[UMALI] Sir.
That's why I didn't pay them.
Paquito apologized.
But Django is just arrogant.
I nearly hit him earlier.
I want to know the identity
of the person they fought.
Check whether
there is CCTV footage.
Find the man who
went up against Paquito's men.
We might find him useful.
Yes, sir.
[SIGHS]
- Here's our food.
- [IPE] Finally!
[TEKLA] You guys
are too impatient.
[IPE] It took so long.
[TEKLA] Wow!
Where are the three scumbags?
They're the ones who
are always in a rush to eat.
- Call them!
- Where are they?
- Let's call them.
- Let's go.
They're taking too long.
[TEKLA] I wonder
what they're doing?
[UTENSILS CLATTERING]
Your beer's warm.
- [SIGHS]
- Where did you go?
[CASTOR] To the bathroom.
[TEKLA] Are you okay, Gabo?
What's going on?
I saw something.
I saw something I didn't like.
You saw something?
What is it?
[BOTTLE CLATTERS]
Forget it.
We should've had drinks
at Linda's store instead.
There are no bad vibes there.
The service here
takes too long.
If that's the case,
then I'll go ahead and eat.
I'm starving.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
- [GROANS]
- Hey!
- What happened?
We were attacked.
Didn't you see them?
Let's go!
We might catch up to them!
Help me! I can't stand!
- [BONG] Let's go!
- [IPE] C'mon.
I'm heading out.
I'm a bit tipsy.
- [KAREN] I'll go with you.
- [SEBASTIAN] Let's go.
[RALLOS] I've got it, sir.
I'll get the beers.
- Sure.
- [KAREN] Let's go.
- [DABOY] Hurry up!
- [TOLITS] Let's go!
- [GROANS]
- He's huge!
[BINOY] The one
who beat us was huge!
Stop saying nonsense!
That's why you got beat up.
We can't tell Gabo.
This might be your fault.
We can't drag him into this.
[TOLITS] What do you mean?
We got beaten up!
- [GROANS]
- Hurry! Hurry!
[TEKLA] You should eat
with me, Gabo.
Let's not wait
for those idiots anymore.
They won't be upset
since you'll pay.
- [SEBASTIAN] Rallos?
- [RALLOS] Yes, sir?
Take my car.
I'll bring Sam home.
[DABOY] Ouch!
[BINOY] They were just here!
That man was huge!
- Where is he?
- He looked like a wrestler!
- There were three of them!
- Where are they?
Miss, have you seen
a huge man?
- Is it him?
- Maybe he left!
We should tell Gabo!
- Gabo!
[TOLITS] We
got beaten up, Gabo!
[TEKLA] What?!
We got beaten up by the NCIA.
- [BINOY GROANS]
- The NCIA again?!
Maybe they're
in the parking lot! Let's go!
[TOLITS] Let's get back at them!
Let's go!
Sam, where are your keys?
Wait!
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
[DOOR CLICKS]
- [DOOR SLAMS]
- They're the NCIA.
[ENGINE REVS]
I'm sure they have
guns with them.
How will we get back
at them, Gabo?
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES]
We'll get even next time.
That's the bastard
who beat me up.
- [DOOR SLAMS]
- I'll get back at them.
[CAR ENGINE REVS]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES]
[ENGINE REVS]
What's our plan, Gabo?
We're leaving.
Let's go.
Their service was bad anyway.
[TEKLA] What a bummer!
We didn't even get to drink!
[BINOY]
Whose fault is it?
- I wonder who!
- Why are you looking at us?!
- Well, it is your fault.
- Gabo, join us!
- Have a seat.
- Oh! Free booze!
- Thank you!
- Simang!
Give these guys a bucket!
Put it on my tab.
[BINOY] Is this spicy?
My wound still hurts.
Hey, what happened to you?
Well, Gabo here wanted to treat
us to some food and drinks.
But since we were
with these three,
we got in trouble.
So, here we are,
parched and hungry.
Who did you fight?
I heard they're from NCIA.
That explains your faces.
Simang, make sure
the beer's cold.
- Here you go.
- Pass it on.
You're going out?
- It's already late.
- I'm going to work.
To work? Where?
At The BeerGin Bar.
I told you Paquito allowed me
to work there, didn't I?
- Betchay.
- Ow!
You don't have to work
at The BeerGin.
What was that?
Who's working at the BeerGin?
Me. Do you have
a problem with that?
If you're worried about money,
I can earn that
at the car repair shop!
Just let me recover.
If only I weren't injured,
you wouldn't have to worry
about a thing!
That car repair shop?
That car repair shop
that's always in the negative?
Who gave you the capital
for that anyway?
Hey!
That's for everyone!
Don't eat it all!
Sorry, but I'm really hungry.
We haven't had dinner yet.
Because we had to leave
before we could eat our order.
That's what you get
for always picking fights.
You talk as if you're earning a
lot from that blasted bar!
At least I'm doing something.
I'm not sitting around
doing nothing.
- There are other ways!
- What ways?
Come on, tell me!
What can I possibly do
to quickly earn money
enough to not worry about
all our expenses?!
Do you know of a way?!
Tell me!
Can't think of anything,
can you?
Unbelievable!
I'm working hard here,
yet here you are judging me!
[MAMENG] Why?
Is The BeerGin the only place
you can work at?
Have some respect
for your body!
- [SCOFFS]
- [DANTE] You know, Betchay,
our family's going to be
fodder for gossip
when people find out
where you're working.
I don't give a damn!
That's Aunt Betchay.
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Who's working
at Mister Paquito's bar?
Well, who do you think?
It's your great stepmother,
Betchay.
Of all the places
she could work at,
she just had to choose
Paquito's bar!
Betchay, what were you thinking?
Why'd you have to work
for Gabo's enemy?
Aunt Betchay, what you're
doing is dangerous!
What if Paquito and Django
get back at you?
Paquito is a good businessman.
And I have nothing to do
with your fight with Django!
You know what's the problem
with you lot?
You keep thinking ill
of all my efforts!
We're not demeaning
your efforts!
All we're trying to say is
have some respect for body!
Have some respect
for yourself!
You want me to worry
about my body?
We don't even have
enough to eat!
What good is my pride, anyway?!
I'm so sick of being poor!
I just want a better life!
Now, I have the chance
to earn some cash,
so I'll make the most of it!
If that's what you want...
then suit yourself!
Oh, I will!
And you!
You're the bane of my existence!
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
I think they want to kill me
because I spoke against
Ricardo Jacinto and the cops
who were out to demolish
Ginintuang Lupa.
Looks like that reporter
is out to get you.
Things aren't looking good
for that project.
I know it was Aunt Betchay
who hustled to provide for us.
And I witnessed how hurt
you were when Mama died.
But, Papa,
please don't lose hope.
I'm here to help you.
I hope you find a woman
who will truly love you
and help you change your life.
If I find a woman to love,
I'll try to be like you.
Because I saw how much
affection you had for Mama,
how you took care of her,
and how you
made us feel loved.